あれか…
That must be it.
Step aside!
そこを退け
Inspector Ginoza of CID Division 1...
刑事課一係　宜野座監視官
該当する情報適格性はありません
You are not eligible
for access to this information.
You are forbidden to enter this area.
立ち入りを禁じます
What?!
何だと
I'll explain it to you.
説明は私がしよう
Chief...
局長…
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒  白心上人    校对:西西     时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
#18 A Promise Written
on Water
Please explain to me
how Shogo Makishima escaped.
槙島聖護が逃亡に至った経緯をご説明願います
It's very likely that he had help from
someone inside the Ministry of Welfare.
厚生省内部から何らかの手引きがあった可能性が極めて高い
Otherwise, escape is impossible.
そうでもなければ逃亡など不可能だからね
We just have to hear what happened
directly from Makishima himself.
真相は槙島自身の口から直に聞き出すしか他にない
So when you capture him next time,
よって再度槙島の身柄を確保するに当たっては
I want you to put the
priority on bringing him in alive.
その命を脅かさないことに最優先の配慮をしてもらう
I'll once again put Division 1 in charge.
改めて君たち一係に任せよう
What on earth is going on?! Please give
me an explanation that I can accept!
いったいどういうことなんですか
納得のいく説明をしてください
宜野座君…
Ginoza...
Yes?
はい
Not only did you allow Enforcer Kagari
to escape, your investigation
縢執行官の逃亡を許したのみならず
その捜査すら行き詰まっている状況だ
into his disappearance has
already come up against a brick wall.
Now that you have been given the
top priority task of recapturing Makishima,
そこに槙島再逮捕という優先事項が割り込んだことで
君は自らの失態を有耶無耶にする絶好のチャンスを得たはずだ
you've got the perfect opportunity
to sweep your blunder under the rug.
This is my way of showing appreciation
to Division 1 and extending my support.
これは一係への私なりの評価と助け舟…
その辺の親心を察してもらいたいものだね
I hope you realize what consideration
your boss is showing you.
But...
しかし…
Also, regarding Enforcer Shinya Kogami...
それと　執行官の狡噛慎也
あの男は今回の任務から外し　厳重な監視下に置くように…
...take him off of this case and
put him under strict supervision.
どういうことです
Why?
言ったはずだよ
I told you, didn't I... your top
priority is Shogo Makishima's safety.
槙島聖護の身の安全に最優先の配慮をしろと…
As of now, the task of tracking
down Kagari is transferred to Division 2.
現時点をもって　縢の追跡捜査は二係に委譲
我々一係は　槙島聖護の追跡を担当する
We at Division 1 are in charge
of tracking down Shogo Makishima.
狡噛執行官は　公安局内に残れ
Enforcer Kogami,
you need to stay in the MWPSB.
I want you to work with
Analyst Karanomori to back us up.
唐之杜分析官と共に　我々のバックアップを担当してもらう
これは局長命令だ
These are the Chief's orders.
Say...
...don't you think it's strange that
the Chief orders me off the case?
局長命令で俺を外せなんて　妙な話だと思わないか
We're already short on manpower,
and yet, she'd reduce it even more?
ただでさえ足りない人員をさらに削る？
あり得んだろう
That makes no sense.
何より重要なのは槙島の安全で
This means that the most important
thing here is Makishima's safety,
やつの再犯を阻止するのは二の次ってことだ
and that stopping him from committing
more crimes is secondary.
We can't really call what
we're doing "arresting" anymore.
そいつはもう逮捕とは言わない
身柄の保護…とでも言い直すべきだろう
Maybe we should call it something
more like "protective duty."
上の連中は槙島を裁くつもりがない
Our top brass don't intend to judge him.
Even if we capture him again,
もし仮に俺たちがまたやつを捕まえてきても
局長は何か別の目的に利用しようとしている
the Chief is trying to use
him for some other purpose.
違うか
Am I wrong?
What do you base that on?
何を根拠に…
You heard what he said
when he called me, didn't you?
やつが俺にかけてきた電話は聞いただろう
「シビュラシステムの正体」あいつはそう言っていた
"The true form of the
Sibyl System"...That's what he said.
槙島は俺たちでさえ知らない内幕まで辿り着いていたんだ
He had already discovered the inner
workings that we don't even know.
ただのブラフだ
He was just bluffing!
Are we taking criminals
at their word now?!
犯罪者の言葉を真に受けてどうする
He must have...
誰か…
...negotiated with someone who can
even control the Sibyl System at will.
シビュラシステムさえ意のままに操っている何者かと
槙島は交渉したんだ
This person was outwitted
by Makishima in the end.
そいつは結局槙島に出し抜かれ
それで怒るどころか　ますます槙島に執着するようになった
And yet instead of getting angry,
they became even more obsessed with him.
シビュラは　あらゆる機関から独立不干渉を保証されたシステムだ
Sibyl is a system that
is guaranteed to be independent and
free from influence by any organization.
No one is given that kind of authority.
そんな権限は誰も与えられていない
それが事実なのかどうか
Makishima probably knows
whether that's true or not.
おそらく槙島は知っている
身柄の運搬に護送車ではなく航空機
They used an aircraft to transport
him instead of a paddy wagon.
On top of that, only
Drones were onboard with him.
しかも同乗していたのはドローンのみ
Nothing about this case is normal.
何もかもが異常だ
そもそも現場から運び出された遺体は誰だ
To start with, whose body was
that being taken out from the site?
記録からは消去されているが
It's been erased from the record,
but we clearly saw it.
俺たちははっきり見たぞ
誰だって納得しちゃいないよ　コウ
No one accepts it, Ko.
It's a top secret. The Inspectors
wouldn't know the answer, either.
機密区分だ 監視官だって答えは知るまい
You're asking the wrong person.
お前は問いただす相手を間違えてる
I guess you're right.
それもそうか…
I'll go grab a bite to eat.
食事してきます
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さん
This is all one big farce.
Every single thing is...
全てが茶番だ…何もかも…
When the Toyohisa Senguji
case happened,
泉宮寺豊久の事件
I saw the report Gino
submitted to the top brass...
あのときギノが上に上げた報告書を見た
...secretly...
こっそりと
You did it again?
またそんなことを…
The part where the Dominator ignored
Makishima was gone without a trace.
ドミネーターが槙島を無視した件は　影も形もなかったよ
あの文面じゃ　削らされたってのが実際のところだろうな
From how the report was written,
he was probably forced to delete it.
シビュラで裁けない人間がいるという事実そのものを
The top brass are trying to erase
the very fact that there are people
who can't be judged by Sibyl.
上層部は潰しにかかってる
それは…仕方ないと思います
Well... I don't think they can help it.
Don't you feel frustrated?
悔しくないのか
悔しいです　でも…
I do. But...
この間の暴動で改めて思い知りました
I realized something anew when
the riots happened the other day.
正義の執行も　秩序の維持も　私はどっちも大切だと思います
I think enforcing justice and
maintaining order are both important.
Then...
なら…
...what do you think we can do with
those who are outside the law to settle things?
法の外側にいる人間に　何をどうすれば収まりがつくと思う
We have no choice but
to make this an exceptional case
今回ばかりは特例措置で
もう一度昔の制度に立ち戻るしかないでしょう
and go back to the old system.
起訴して法廷を開いて　弁護もさせて
We prosecute him, open a
court, let him defend himself,
その上で量刑をするしかないのでは…
and then sentence him.
I think that's all we can do.
気の遠くなる話だな
That sounds like a
pretty daunting process.
お膳立てにどれだけ時間がかかることやら
Who knows how
long it'll take to prepare.
でも　他に方法なんて…
But there's no other way...
There is, remember?
あっただろ
A quicker way that
wouldn't cause anyone trouble.
もっと手っ取り早く　誰の迷惑にもならない方法が…
あの時…槙島を殺しておけばよかった
We should've killed Makishima then.
あんたが手を下すのではなく　俺が最後の止めを刺せば…
Instead of having you do it,
if I finish him off myself...
You're an Inspector.
I can't have you kill someone.
監視官のあんたに人殺しはさせられない
But I'm an Enforcer.
I have nothing to lose.
…が　執行官の俺には失うものなんて何もない
That's how our teamwork works.
そういうチームワークなんだ
俺だって猟犬の面目躍如さ
That'll show my worth as
a hunting dog, too.
That's not enforcing the law.
It'll just create a new killer, that's all.
それは法の執行ではありません
ただ殺人犯が二人になるだけです
狡噛さん…
Mr. Kogami...
いつだったか言ってましたよね
You told me one time that you want
to work as a detective, not a dog.
犬ではなく　刑事として働きたいって…
どうでもいいことを覚えてんだな
You sure do remember
some frivolous things.
どうでもよくありません
It's not frivolous. It's important.
大切なことです
あの言葉のおかげで
It's thanks to those
words that I didn't quit this job.
私　この仕事を辞めずに済みました
ねえ　狡噛さん…
Say, Mr. Kogami.
Will you always be a detective?
これからもずっと刑事でいてくれますか
そう私に約束してくれますか
Could you promise me that?
ああ…
Yeah.
Oof.
よっと…
In any case...
is the Chief treating us like dogs
しかし　まあ
局長は俺たちに犬のようにボール遊びでもやらせてるつもりか
by giving us a ball to
play with or something?
Say... what was I supposed to do?
なあ…
どうすればよかったんだ
What's the right answer in
this kind of situation?
こういう時　何が正解なんだ
正解はない あるのは妥協だけだ
There's no right answer.
There's only compromise.
Hey...
Nobuchika...
伸元
What is it?
何だ…
身を守れ
Protect yourself.
What?
Like I said earlier, this is a game of
ball between master and dog.
さっきも言った
こいつはご主人さまと犬のボール遊びだ
If you disobey, you'll just be punished.
逆らえば折檻されるだけ
だったら　身の置き所を変えるんだよ
If that's the case,
you should change your position
to that of a third party,
neither dog nor master.
犬でもご主人さまでもない　第三の立場に…
第三の
A third party?
The ball.
ボールだよ
Turn yourself into the ball getting thrown,
just bouncing and rolling.
ただ投げられて　弾んで転がるだけのボールになりきる
At first glance, it may appear unseemly,
一見無様に見えるかもしれんが
but the reality is, that's the way
to get hurt least and not get drained.
実は一番傷つかないし 疲れない
That's the wise action, you know.
それが賢い立ち回りってもんだ
Sorry to say this, but this
case is too much for you to handle.
言っちゃ悪いが この一件はお前の手に余る
Rather than acting carelessly
and ending up being forced to resign,
下手に動いて詰め腹を切らされるよりも
ただ低い方を目指して転がっていくだけの
it's better to act completely useless,
just rolling towards the lower place.
役立たずに徹する方がいい
また　ずいぶんとひどいアドバイスがあったもんだ
That's some pretty terrible advice.
I thought you'd be smarter
than I am about that kind of stuff.
そういう知恵は俺よりもお前の方が回ると思ってたんだがな
きっと年の功ってやつだろう
It must be the so-called wisdom of age.
We really can't afford not to have
Kogami when we go after Makishima.
槙島を捕らえる上で　やはり狡噛の戦力は欠かせない
Even if he's a dog that bites his master?
飼い主の手を噛む犬でも　か
こと槙島搦みとなると　狡噛ほど鼻の利く猟犬はいない
When it comes to the
matters related to Makishima,
there's no other hunting dog
with as keen a nose as Kogami's.
あんたがよく口にする　「刑事の勘」
That detective instinct
that you often talk about...
It's a talent that
I don't happen to have after all.
結局　俺が持ち合わせることのなかった才能だ
But the Chief ordered you
to take him off the case, right?
だが任務から外せというのは局長命令だろ
檻の外にさえ出してしまえばこっちのもんだ
Once we can get him out
of the cage, the game is ours.
後は　どういう口実を捏ち上げるかだが…
The question left is,
what excuse shall I come up with?
It's unlike you to come up
with a radical idea like that, Ginoza.
宜野座君にしては
またずいぶんと思い切った手を考えたわよね
I'm sorry...
申し訳ない
...to have you take part
in something risky like this.
危ない綱渡りなのに 片棒を担がせてしまって
That's okay.
いいわよ
I agree that the way Kagari from
your Division disappeared is fishy...
そっちの縢君の消え方がうさんくさいってのは私も同意見
...and also that we
can't let Shogo Makishima be.
それに槙島聖護を放っておけないっていうのもね
At the CID as a whole,
we currently have two vacancies.
現在 刑事課全体で執行官に２人の欠員が出ている
In this situation, we can't let you
waste time sitting around in the lab.
この状況でお前にラボで油を売らせておくわけにもいかない
そこでだ 二係の青柳監視官と相談し
So I asked Inspector Aoyanagi in
Division 2 to temporarily have you and
一時的な執行官の交代に応じてもらった
one of her Enforcers
switch places and she accepted it.
狡噛は当面二係で縢秀星の捜索を手伝え
So go to Division 2 for a while
and help them search for Shusei Kagari.
代わりにわれわれも二係から人員を１人借り受ける
In your place, we'll borrow
one of the Division 2 people.
When we have so few clues
on Kagari's case, it's just natural
縢君の件 これだけ手掛かりが少ないと
that the investigation
takes a sinuous course.
捜査が迷走するのも仕方ないわ
Kogami, whatever you do,
don't pull any stupid stunts...
狡噛君 くれぐれも余計なまねはしないでね
私の目に付く範囲では
...while I'm looking, that is.
Yes, ma'am.
承知してます
This is a special circumstance
as defined in Code K32.
コードＫ３２に基づく特殊事例です
狡噛慎也執行官の身柄を拘束します
We will take Shinya Kogami
into custody.
Wha...
なっ…
Tsk.
If you really thought that you
could outwit me with such a cheeky trick,
こんな小ざかしい計略で出し抜けると思ったなら
it's clear that you
take me for quite the fool.
なめられたものだな 私も
I'm surprised that you're such
a big fan of mine, Chief Kasei.
あんたがそこまで熱烈な俺のファンだったとは意外だよ
禾生局長
That you think you can
talk back in this situation is quite...
ここで減らず口をたたける君の精神構造はまったくもって
理解に苦しむな
...hard to understand.
Chief!
局長 説明させてください　これは…
Please let me explain! This is...
No, you don't need to explain.
いいや　説明には及ばない
Ginoza, isn't this the sort of
situation where the more you talk,
宜野座君　ここは口を開くほど墓穴を掘る局面ではないかね
the more trouble you end up in?
個人の裁量による判断も必ずしもとがめるべきものとは限らない
It's not always true
that a judgment based on
an individual's
discretion should be criticized.
What's important is to
produce a satisfying result.
要は満足いく結果さえ伴えばいいのだ
評価の基準はそれだけだ
That's the only
basis for evaluation.
だからこそ危険な賭けに打って出る際は
Precisely because of that,
when you take a risky gamble,
引き際の判断が重要になる
knowing when to quit is important.
自らの不始末をどれだけ速やかに
How quickly and firmly you can close
the books on your failure is the question.
断固たる態度で清算できるか…
Now, Inspector Ginoza...
さて　宜野座監視官
An Enforcer who's
under your supervision
君の監視下にある執行官が今重大な背任を犯そうとしているわけだが
is about to commit
a serious breach of trust.
How are you going
to deal with this situation?
この場面にどう対処する
愚にもつかない弁明をただ並べ立てるより
Instead of just going
on and on with foolish explanations,
もっと明晰で非の打ち所のない決断力を示すことはできるかな
are you able to show clear and
flawless decisiveness?
Crime Coefficient is 265.
「犯罪係数　２６５」
An Enforcer registered at the
Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課登録執行官 任意執行対象です」
He is an Enforce At Will target.
Yes, that's good.
Safety will be released.
うん　結構…
You're properly proving your own usefulness.
君は順当に自らの有用性を証明している
However, I still have to
say that you're not thorough.
だが　詰めの甘さも否めない
Enforcement mode
is Non-Lethal... Para...
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライ…」
Lethal... eliminate...
Now, Ginoza. Show me
how you take charge as a leader.
さあ　宜野座君 君の責任者としての采配を…
Show me your decisiveness,
unhindered by emotion.
情に流されない決断力を私に見せてくれないか
For a target whose
Crime Coefficient is under 300,
犯罪係数３００以下の対象にはパラライザーモードが適用されます
Paralyzer mode should be used.
Mr. Ginoza, that Dominator is broken.
宜野座さん　そのドミネーター故障してますよ
You should send it in
for maintenance immediately.
すぐメンテナンスに出さないと
Yeah.
Akane...
朱ちゃ…
You should appreciate Akane.
朱ちゃんに感謝しなさいよ
She avoided the
central nerve and shot your leg.
中枢神経避けて足に当ててくれたんだから
もうドミネーターの扱いも慣れたもんか
Seems like she's gotten
used to using the Dominator, huh?
何かさ
You know...
...when an inexperienced
newbie rapidly becomes tough,
初々しい新人がどんどんタフになっちゃうのって
頼もしいような寂しいような…
it feels reassuring on the one hand,
but also a bit sad. It's complicated, huh?
複雑なもんね
She'll get tougher and tougher.
あいつはこれからもっともっとタフになるさ
I've got a question.
１個質問
はーい　何でしょう
Yes, what is it?
Does that helmet still work?
あのヘルメットまだ使えるのか
一応ね
More or less. But when the
Sibyl System is completely restored,
でもシビュラシステムの完全復旧と共に 対策プログラムが実装される予定
they plan on installing countermeasures.
そうなったらあとはもう普通のヘルメット
After that,
it'll just be a regular helmet.
How long before it's restored?
完全復旧まで
Six more days.
あと６日
証拠品持ってくつもり
Are you going to take
a piece of evidence with you?
I need it for the investigation.
捜査のために必要なんだよ
This from the guy
who got taken off the case?
捜査からは外されてるくせに
こっちにも通達は来てるのか
Have they notified you guys of that, too?
Hmm... I'm not sure.
ん～どうだったっけ
そういやまだ聞いてなかったかも
Come to think of,
maybe I haven't heard yet.
Don't ever take it outside, okay?
絶対に外に持ち出さないでよね
I know.
分かってるよ
Say, Shinya...
ねえ　慎也君ん
Hm?
私さ～せめて一度ぐらいはあなたと寝てみるべきだったのかな
You know... should I have
slept with you at least once?
Who knows... although I don't
think we're each other's type.
どうだかな…
お互い趣味じゃなかったと思うぜ
ん…そうだよね
I guess you're right.
Oh, the helmet, huh?
I forgot you could use that.
ああ　ヘルメットね
その手があったか
This is to celebrate your discharge
from the hospital. Here, have some.
退院祝いだ　まあ飲めよ
I've been looking at the
info on Makishima you collected.
お前の集めた槙島の資料見せてもらってるぜ
It looks messy at a glance,
but it's quite organized.
一見とっちらかっているようでいて
きっちり整理がついてる
It's prepared in a way that you
can take just the important parts
いざとなれば 肝心な部分だけいつでも持ち出せる構えだな
when push comes to shove.
Why are you so obsessed with Makishima?
なぜそこまでやつにこだわる
Is it evil that you can't tolerate?
Or is it Makishima himself?
お前が許せないのは悪か それとも槙島自身か
どっちも違うよ　とっつぁん
It's neither, pops.
今ここで諦めても
Even if I give up now,
いずれ俺は槙島聖護を見逃した自分を許せなくなる
eventually I'll come to resent myself
for letting Shogo Makishima get away.
そんなのは真っ平だ
I could never allow that to happen.
That answer suits you perfectly, Ko.
お前らしい答えだな　コウ
This is from the time I worked for
the Metropolitan Police Department.
警視庁時代の思い出だ
いざというときに備えてセーフハウスを用意してたことがある
There was a time when I prepared
a safe house for an emergency.
It might be of use to you.
何かの役に立つかもしれん
Pops...
とっつぁん…
Are you gonna leave
without saying a word to Missy?
お嬢ちゃんには黙ったまま行くのか
いまさら合わせる顔がない
I can't face her now.
せめて気持ちの整理だけはつけさせてやれよ
At least help her come to terms.
そうだな…
Yeah...
There's no way that I could love someone
But I want someone to love me
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
God... where did you go?
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
「すまない…俺は約束を守れなかった」
I'm sorry. I couldn't keep my promise.
I wanted to go into a line of work
where I could protect people.
「誰かを守る役目を果たしたい」
That's why I became a detective.
「そう思って俺は刑事になった」
But Makishima changed everything.
「だが槙島の存在が全てを変えた」
That man will continue to kill people.
「あの男はこれからも人をあやめ続けるだろう」
And yet, the law can't judge him.
「なのに法律ではやつを裁けない」
As long as I'm a detective, I can't touch him.
「俺は刑事でいるかぎりあの男に手出しができない」
This case made me aware...
「今度の一件で思い知った」
that the law can't protect people.
「法律で人は守れない」
In that case, my only
option is to step outside the law.
「なら　法の外に出るしかない」
「常守朱…あんたの生き方は間違いなく正しい」
Akane Tsunemori... There is no
doubt that your way of living is correct.
Don't lose sight of that
just because I betrayed you.
「俺に裏切られたからってそこを見失ってはいけない」
I selfishly chose a different path
solely in order to get my own way.
「俺はあくまで身勝手に 自分の意地を通すためだけに
あんたと違う道を選んだ」
I'm aware that this is a mistake.
「これが過ちだと理解はしている」
But I know I can only come to terms
with my old self by taking the wrong path.
「だが　俺はきっと間違った道を進むことでしか
今までの自分と折り合いがつけられない」
I won't say... forgive me.
「許してくれ…とは言わない」
The next time we meet,
you'll be in a position to judge me.
「次に会うときはおそらく
あんたは俺を裁く立場にいるだろう」
「そのときは容赦なく務めを果たせ」
When that time comes,
fulfill your duty with no mercy.
Don't turn your back on your beliefs.
「信念に背を向けてはいけない」
Although it was only for a short time,
「ほんのいっときだったが あんたの下で働けて幸いだった」
I feel fortunate that
I was able to work under you.
Thank you.
「礼を言う…」
バカ…
You idiot...
You'll never walk alone
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
I'll walk an uncharted path
All alone with you
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.